JOHANES INGANTA KARO-KARO

0812 1819 1202 | johanes230500@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/johanes-inganta | Medan, Indonesia, 20132

SUMMARY STATEMENT

I am a passionate software engineer with 1 year of experience in web development, having worked on various projects, including building responsive websites and developing web applications. While primarily utilizing Javascript language, i am open to learning other languages and tools. I am eager to take on new challenges and learn new skills to further my career in software engineering.

SKILLS

- Web Development
- Vue

Git

• Node

Javascript

React

SQL

EXPERIENCE

Full-stack Developer April 2023- Present

PT Astra International Tbk, Jakarta

- Responsible for designing and implementing both the frontend and backend components of web applications using React js, Vue js and Express js.
- Integrate website with Meta Graph API for whatsapp business management system.
- Maintain serverless services using AWS Lambda.
- Collaborate with cross functional teams, including Product, QA and Fullstack in a Scrum Agile squad based environment.
- Utilize Jira and Microsoft Azure for efficient task management.

Frontend Engineer Intern

August 2022- January 2023

Pegipegi, Jakarta

- Implemented UI/UX designs using Vue.js and Nuxt.js.
- Collaborated in Scrum Agile squads with Product, QA, UI/UX and Backend teams for comprehensive feature testing befre release.
- Wrote clean and reusable code.
- Efficiently managed tasks with Jira and Github.

Backend Intern May 2022- September 2022

Astra Credit Companies, Jakarta

- Created robust APIs using Toad and Software AG.
- Collaborated with Front-end, System Analyst, and QA teams in the development of an employee attendance website.
- Managed tasks efficiently using Monday.com, following Agile methods.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Degree in Computer Science, Universitas Sumatera Utara *GPA 3.83*

CERTIFICATIONS

Fullstack Developer Bootcamp

Harisenin

- Learned basic web development process using HTML, CSS and Javascript.
- Learned frontend development process using React js.
- Learned backend development process using Node js and Express js.
- Learned SQL query design and function

Frontend Development: React js

2022

Alterra Academy

- Participated in the React JS class through the Magang dan Studi Independen (MSIB) program by Kemdikbud in collaboration with Alterra Academy.
- Completed daily tasks to enhance React JS skills and successfully implemented various topics in miniprojects.
- Collaborated with a team of 9 individuals to build a web and mobile app Learning Management System (LMS)

2022